#### Contact

31991508940 (Home) ejrocha07@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/enokjrocha (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

**BDD** 

**POM** 

Testes exploratórios

### Languages

Inglês (Professional Working)

### Certifications

Testes Automáticos

Manipulando o D.O.M. com Javascript

Automação de testes de API com Postman

Fundamentos e prática do teste de software

Posicionando elementos com Flexbox em CSS

# **Enok Rocha**

Analista de Automação de Testes @ Base2 | QA Analyst | Software Tester | Testes | QA Engineer | Selenium

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

# Summary

I was an intern at the IT lab of the UFMG School of Veterinary Medicine for 2 years, dealing with customer service and studying the needs of those who frequent the lab. During this time, I also had the opportunity to work on projects related to network infrastructure and machine maintenance. I was an intern at Synergia, having joined as part of the 2020 residency project and was later hired. I worked as a QA at Opus Software, contributing to the planning and execution of various types of tests (smoke, exploratory, API, regressive, etc.) and proposing improvements for the systems I work on.

I am passionate about technology, mathematics, and solving logical problems. In my free time, I always try to learn something new in my field or something that I am interested in/curious about. After all, trying new things is essential for our development.

# Experience

Base2 Tecnologia
Test Automation Analyst
October 2024 - Present (7 months)
Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brasil

- Focal point for Cheque-related demands, working on automation with Rest Assured
- Focal point for frontend tests, automated using Selenide
- Daily monitoring of regression tests, identifying environment issues and potential performance improvements

OPUS Software

2 years 9 months

Quality Assurance Engineer III
June 2024 - October 2024 (5 months)

Quality Assurance Engineer II

November 2022 - June 2024 (1 year 8 months)

São Paulo, São Paulo, Brasil

Worked on a project focused on meeting regulatory demands for Open Finance and Open Insurance. My responsibilities included:

- Planning and executing API tests using tools like Postman and Swagger.
- Writing automated test resource files (feature files) using a Gherkin/BDD-based framework.
- Actively participating in planning sessions and closely collaborating with the development team in a shift-left testing approach.
- Creating written evidence or test reports to document and log the testing activities performed.

Quality Assurance Engineer I February 2022 - November 2022 (10 months)

São Paulo, São Paulo, Brasil

I worked on various projects for different clients and, consequently, on different work fronts. In common, I always worked using agile methodologies (Scrum/ Kanban), participating in the planning and execution of test cases, planning meetings for new demands, identifying quality concerns for the product, and suggesting improvements or adjustments to prevent future issues with the product. Most of the time, I worked on testing products for BRK Ambiental: the BackOffice system, a web system for property re-registration, and an app for property re-registration. I conducted API, E2E, and mobile testing. The application has a test automation framework using Appium, where periodic maintenance is performed to ensure test compliance. All other tests were conducted manually, with each step of the execution recorded, documented, and attached to the detailed demand in Jira. I also worked briefly on a project for PagBem, testing the application and following the same methodologies and ideas as the previous project. In this second project, I worked with Zephyr, and part of the tests were executed and documented using Swagger.

Synergia

2 years

Junior Development Analyst October 2021 - January 2022 (4 months)

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brasil

Development of features and code rewriting for new technologies for part of the State of Minas Gerais Procurement Portal. As a development analyst, my role was to adapt part of the system (primarily related to auctions) and implement improvements requested by the client. Much of the development was done in JAVA, and I worked with technologies/tools such as: React, TomCat, Maven, JSP, Jenkins, JUnit, Spring, and Hibernate.

### Development Intern

February 2020 - October 2021 (1 year 9 months)

Belo Horizonte e Região, Brasil

Intern in the Synergia Residency Program, 2020 edition. I worked on the PNBOX project, a business plan creation tool for entrepreneurs, developed for SEBRAE. The project was built from scratch using technologies such as React, Node.js, and Meteor.

As an intern, I worked on front-end, back-end, and mobile development, but I was also involved in planning and executing tests (exploratory and unit tests), code reviews, UX, and validation of implemented features.

### **UFMG**

IT Support Intern

September 2017 - August 2019 (2 years)

Assistance to the public and handling demands for the IT lab at the UFMG School of Veterinary Medicine. Responsibilities included registering new students in the system, assisting with the use of lab computers, and performing maintenance on lab machines as well as on students' personal devices.

## Education

Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais

Graduação, Ciência da Computação · (August 2016 - August 2021)

#### Faculdade UniBF

Pós-graduação Lato Sensu - Especialização, Gestão da Qualidade de Software · (May 2022 - September 2022)

IFMG Campus Congonhas

Técnico, Mineração · (2013 - 2015)

Escola Estadual Dr Gama Cerqueira

Ensino Fundamental · (2009 - 2012)